Daniel Mitchell Collection of U.S. Executive Office of the President Phase II Payboard Records 5218
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Daniel Mitchell Collection of U.S. Executive Office of the President Phase II Payboard Records
1972
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Mitchell, Daniel
5218
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Economic papers of the Phase II Pay Board. These records were produced by the Office of the Chief Economist, first known as the Economic Anaylysis Division, directed by Daniel Mitchell.
5556528
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 24, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Scope and Contents
Economic papers of the Phase II Pay Board. These records were produced by the Office of the Chief Economist, first known as the Economic Anaylysis Division, directed by Daniel Mitchell.
Also included are some Pay Board documents relating to specific cases before the Board. The economic papers appeared in the agenda book which the Board received before each meeting, or in supplements to that book.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Wages -- Government policy -- United States; Mitchell, Daniel J. B.; United States. Executive Office of the President
5556528
- EAD-1 UTU Workrules, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- EAD-2 UTU Catchup, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- EAD-3 UTU Tandem, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- EAD-4 United Aircraft Catchup, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- EAD-5 United Aircraft Labor Market conditions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- EAD-6 Bargaining Patterns in the Railroad Industry, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- EAD-7 COLC on Working Poor, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- EAD-8 Working Poor, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- EAD-9 Productivity Issues before the Pay Board, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- EAD-10 Possible Exemptions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- EAD-11 Wage Changes during Phase 1 and Phase 2, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- EAD-12 Price Commission on Labor Costs and Productivity, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- EAD-15 Data Relating to Extension of Catch-up, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- EAD-16 Recent Trends, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- EAD-17 Pending Cases, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- EAD-19 Compensation Productivity, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- EAD-20 Pacific Maritime Assoc. ILWU Appeal, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- EAD-21 BLS Major Settlements 1st Qtr, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- EAD-22 Catchup BLS Calculations, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- EAD--23 Corporate Profits, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- EAD-24 Pending Cases, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- EAD-25 Minimum Wage, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- EAD-26 Deferred Increases, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- EAD-27 Pay Bd. Policies and General Economic Conditions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- EAD-28 Corporate Profits, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- EAD-29 Catch-Up, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- EAD-30 Economic Indicatiors, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- EAD-32 Back Loading, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- EAD-33 Construction Data, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- EAD-34 Productivity, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- EAD-35 Catch-up (Box 1, Folder 31)
- EAD-36 Latest Developments on Prices and Wages, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- EAD-3 Review of Pay Board Regulations and Exceptions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- EAD-38 Hourty Earning Projection, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- EAD-39 City Data Supplied by Cisc, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- EAD-40 Construction Approvals, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- EAD-41 Interim Report by Railway Labor Conference, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- EAD-42 Essential Employees, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- EAD-43 Windfall Profits in Constitution, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- EAD-44 Profile of Pay Board Decisions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- EAD-45 Economic Indicators, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- EAD-46 City Data Supplies by CISC, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- EAD-47 F.M.C.S. Survey, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- EAD-48 New CISC Approves, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- EAD-49 BNA Deferred CISC Approvals (Box 1, Folder 45)
- EAD-50 Essential Employee, Exception, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- EAD-51 Latest Development on Prices and Wages, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- EAD-52 Pending Cases, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- EAD-53 Projection of Increase in Compensation during 1972 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- EAD-54 Reconciliation of Pay Board Statistical Data and BLS Data, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- EAD-55 Working Poor, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- EAD-31 J.E.C. Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- EAD-56-64 Review of the 5.5% Standard (Box 1, Folder 53)
- EAD-65 Corporate Profits, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- EAD-66 Composition of Unemployment and Wage Changes, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- EAD-67 Recent Economic Trendy, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- EAD-68 CISC Approvals, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- EAD-69 JEC Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- EAD-70 Duration and Strikes, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- EAD-71 Employment and Wages, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- EAD-72 Qualified Fringes Verses Other Compensation in New Union Requests, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- EAD-73 Arrivals and Pendings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- EAD-74 Excess Demand Situation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- EAD-75 Wholesale Prices, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- EAD-76 Costing for Work Rules, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- EAD-77 Survey 2 of FMCS, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- EAD-78 Recent Economic Trends, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- EAD-79 Current Legislation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- EAD-80 Construction Wages, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- EAD-81 New CISC Approvals, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- EAD-82 Wholesale Prices, Employment and Earnings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- EAD-83 Outlook for 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- EAD-84 City Data Supplies by CISC, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- EAD-85 Arrivals and Pendings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- EAD-86 Recent Economic Trends, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- EAD-87 Preliminary Summary of Pay Board Activities, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- EAD-88 Catch-up, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- EAD-89 Figures on Major Union Situations, 1972+1973 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- EAD-90 New CISC Approvals, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- EAD-91 Recent Trends and Developments, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- EAD-92 Arrivals and Pendings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- OCE-93 Wholesale Prices Employment and Earnings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- PCE-94 Additional Data Concerning 1973 from BLS (Box 1, Folder 83)
- OCE-95 Wage Negotiations 1973 The Rubber Industry (Box 1, Folder 84)
- OCE-96 JEC Papers, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- OCE-97 Figures from National Accounts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- OCE-98 Consumer Prices and Real Earnings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- OCE-99 Experience Under Contracts to Expire in 1973 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- OCE-100 Wage Negotiations 1973- Electrical Machinery Industry, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- OCE-101 Productivity, Unit Labor costs, Compensation per Man-hour, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- OCE-102 Pay Board's Activities during 1st yr of Phase 2, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- OCE-103 Occupational Labor Development, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- OCE-104 Trucking, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- OCE-105 Petroleum, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- OCE-106 Strike Activity, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- OCE-107 CISC Deferreds, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- OCE-108 Fringe Trends, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- OCE-109 Arrivals and Pendings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- OCE-110 Earnings, Employment and Wholesale Prices, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- OCE-111 J.E.C. Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- OCE-112 Projection of Compensation/Man-Hour, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- OCE-113 Input - Output (WPI), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- OCE-114 Consumer Prices Real Earnings and Profits, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 103)
- OCE-115 Arrivals and Pendings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- OCE-116 Employment and Earnings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 105)
- OCE-117 Input-Output, further results, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- OCE-118 WPI and Collective Bargaining Settlements, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 107)
- OCE-119 Mayor Bargaining Situations in 1973 (Box 1, Folder 108)
- OCE-120 Manhours, Productivity Unit Labor Costs1 1973 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- OCE-121 Recent Economic Trends, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 110)
- OCE-122 Statistical Summary of Phase 2 Operations, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 111)
- OCE-122 Supplement, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 112)
- Pay Board Aerospace Cases, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 113)
- Pay Board Staff Submission Papers PMA - ILWU Case, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 114)
- Summary & Analysis of PB Forms, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- East and Gulf Coast Longshore Submission of the Parties, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 116)
- Agenda and Policy Papers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 117)
- Pay Board Agenda and Policy Papers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 118)
- The Pay Board After one Year of Operation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 119)
- Agenda and Policy Papers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 120)